<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Regular Events on RSE Handbook</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/</link><description>Recent content in Regular Events on RSE Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Standup</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/standup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/standup/</guid><description>Standup # The RSE team has a daily Standup between 09:45 and 10:00 via Zoom. The aim of these daily meetings is for RSEs to briefly update the other members of the team on their activities on the previous day and to outline what is planned for the rest of the current day. On days where a weekly team meeting is scheduled, the team meeting takes precedence and Standup will be omitted.</description></item><item><title>Team Meeting</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/team_meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/team_meeting/</guid><description>Team Meeting # The team has a Weekly Team Meeting, typically scheduled for Mondays (sometimes shifted due to unavailability or bank holidays). The team meeting is conducted via Zoom and is allocated a 1 hour time slot, typically 10:00am to 11:00am, though a target time to finish the meeting is 30 to 45 minutes. The aims of the weekly team meeting are:
Ensure RSE team members are up to date on project progress, Facilitate coordination between team members working on the same project, Discuss interactions with the wider Swansea University research community via support and job efficiency monitoring, Coordinate team-wide responsibilities such as delivering teaching and writing administrative reports.</description></item><item><title>Tech Chat</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/tech_chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/tech_chat/</guid><description>Tech Chat # Tech Chats are a currently parked series of talks presented internally by the RSE team. They are conducted via Zoom, and have historically been on an ad-hoc schedule, typically Tuesdays from 10am to 11am. Tech chats are intended as an opportunity for RSE team members to give a presentation on a topic of interest, which can be related to their research, a project they are working on, particular technical skills or general software practices.</description></item></channel></rss>