<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Regular Events on RSE Handbook</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/</link><description>Recent content in Regular Events on RSE Handbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Standup</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/standup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/standup/</guid><description>Standup # The team has a daily Standup between 09:45 and 10:00 via Zoom. Each team member summarises the work done yesterday and what to achieve today. If a team member is not available to attend Stantup, he/she can update on ReCoN. If some team members wish to discuss other specific items like technical solutions or coordinating other actions, those who wish to can stay on the Zoom call.</description></item><item><title>Team Meeting</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/team_meeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/team_meeting/</guid><description>Team Meeting # The team has a Weekly, typically Mondays (sometimes shifted due to unavailability or bank holidays), 1 hour allocated, target time 30-45 minutes, conducted via Zoom.
Order of discussion:
Calendar – discuss events for the coming week, some brief mentions of activities in the previous and next week. Typically use screen share of Google calendar. Estimated time: 3-5 minutes.
Projects – updates on the project listing, commenting on status of work items, keep up to date on collaborative projects.</description></item><item><title>Tech Chat</title><link>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/tech_chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sa2c.github.io/RSE-handbook/docs/regular_events/tech_chat/</guid><description>Tech Chat # Current process: Ad-hoc schedule, historically Tuesdays 10-11am, conducted via Zoom
A member of the team will give a presentation discussing a topic pertinent to their research, current projects or technical skills they are interested in.
The most recent tech chat ‘series’ was ‘Getting to know us’, where members of the team gave presentations on their research interests
Currently internal to the team, largely informal
Proposed changes: Consider resuming wider community tech chats</description></item></channel></rss>